scenes of destruction and devastation it's unbelievable even to those who
have seen it all I already watched the images on television but I will say that
nothing that you watch on television or see in a video on social media is close
to what you feel or what you see when you're here on the ground Sarsour is
here with American NGO Beytilmal who was operating in Turkey long before the
earthquake so far we have distributed blankets the internally displaced people
we have distributed thermals shoes jackets to the orphans we also
distributed hot meals to them today we are here at in Islahia with sister Linda
Sassour we plan on distributing 400 heaters to 400 internally displaced families here
so soon is best known for her work in the United States where she stands strong
against Islamophobia racial injustice among other causes she says it's in part her
faith that drove her to Turquia and given her Palestinian heritage she knows a
thing or two about resilience the earthquake happened there was a lot of
media coverage the death toll was rising so exponentially that the media couldn't
ignore that the West couldn't ignore what was happening here in Turkey and
northern Syria but as the days go by the media starts to focus on other things
and this is an absolute disaster that needs focus because the people need the
help and she says it's radical and sustainable solidarity that will keep the
work going I want people to understand the sustainable means long term it's not
just one donation these are people that are living in tents and have no idea when
they're going to be actually able to live in permanent housing and so the
question is you know is our solidarity going to be one day is it temporary or
are we going to stand with these people till they get back on their feet as the
death toll continues to rise it's becoming clear that long-term aid will be
needed but it's the stamina and the compassion of people like Linda that make
locals know that the aid will sustain them in the months to come Priyanka Navani TRT World in Islahia
here